# Edgar Filipe da Silva Domingues

### Software Engineer

I'm a software engineer with a passion for solving real world problems and **over 10 years** of experience. By putting my best in everything I do, having "kaizen" in my mind, I continuously improve my work and the work of my team. Follow agile and software development best practices to increase business value and client satisfaction. A challenge is both an opportunity to learn and to practice what I know. Have **Experience** working with teams of different cultures and languages, both onsite and remote, and developing software for different areas, including robotics, telecommunications, call centers, e-commerce, fintech, and banking. On my **free time** I'm either working on side projects or outdoor enjoying nature by doing sport. Volunteer in orienteering events.

### **Experience**

### Talkdesk - Software Engineer

2020-08 - present

- Develop back-end software for Call Center Workforce Management.
- Microservices architecture with Java, MicroProfile, and Quarkus.
- Provide mentoring to junior developers.

## **Isobar Switzerland**, Leiria – *Software Engineer / Senior Consultant* 2016-12 – 2020-08

- Developed Client Onboarding solutions for banks using Java Spring BPM engines.
- Full stack developer in B2B e-shop using jQuery and SAP Hybris.
- Worked remotely with distributed teams around the world.

### La Redoute, Leiria – Software Engineer

2014-09 - 2016-12

- Development of the back-end to handle the life cycle of orders from request until shipping.
- Created Java Spring Batch applications to process large quantities of data in an efficient way.
- Migrated COBOL programs to Java Spring and integrated them with legacy systems.
- Launch to production of an important transformation project by managing the team, allocating work and reporting to upper management.

## Portugal Telecom Inovação, Aveiro – Software Engineer

- Developed software for research projects and for products, in the areas of context-awareness, social networks, connection management, VoIP, etc.
- Created application for Windows, Android and iPhone (in Java, C/C++, C# and Objective-C).
- Implemented the OpenSocial specification using Java J2EE and integrated with Social Networks like Facebook, Twiter and Google+.
- Worked in the development of SIP softphones for Android and iOS.
- Developed Windows applications that interact with AT modems and SIM cards.

#### **Education**

## **University of Aveiro** – M.Sc. in Computers and Telematics Engineering 2009-2011

Dissertation: "Development of Behaviors for Humanoid Robot"

Publications: "Humanoid Behaviors: from Simulation to a Real Robot", EPIA 2011, Springer

**University of Aveiro** – Degree in Computers and Telematics Engineering 2006 - 2009

### **Certifications and Training**

- Certified Professional Developer Appway (2018-04)
- Certified Scrum Master (CSM) Scrum Alliance (2017-05)
- French Classes Linécole (2016-07)
- Test-Driven Development Practices in Java pluralsight.com (2016-05)
- Training in Trail Orienteering Course Setting and Planning Portuguese Orienteering Federation (2015-12)
- Training in Technology Project Management PT Inovação (2013-10)
- Advanced training in SIP PT Inovação (2013-06)
- Training "jRuby on Rails" PT Inovação (2012-07)

### Personal Info

Web edgardomingues.com

#### E-mail

edgar.domingues@gmail.com

### **Technical Skills**

Java, JEE, Spring, MicroProfile, Quarkus, SQL, HTML, CSS, Less, Sass, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, React, Git, BPM, Appway, COBOL, DB2, AS400, SOAP, REST, Maven, JUnit, Mockito, Cerberus, C/C++, C#, Android SDK and NDK, iOS, Objective-C, Kotlin, Python, Flutter, Dart, Solidity, Gherkin, Cucumber, Scrum, TDD, BDD

### **Awards**

- WealthBriefing Swiss Awards 2020
- Highest grade finalist in the engineering courses of 2011.
- Merit scholarship in 2007/2008 and 2010/2011.
- Honor student on high school.
- 3º place in the Microsoft Webmaster 2006.

### **Interests**

- Orienteering
- Traveling
- Automation